WEWERE IN ASTORE
AND A GUY IN THAT STORE
"WHAT THE HELL ARE
YOU TALKING ABOUT?"
HE SAYS...
THE USA IS IN
A WAR WITH JAPAN.
WE COULDN'T
BELIEVE IT.
WELL OUR COUNTRY
WAS ATTACKED.
IT'S DIFFERENT.
IT WASN'T LIKE
KOREA OR VIETNAM.
WE WAS ATTACKED.
AND YOU KNOW
IT WAS A FEELING THAT...
MAYBE WE'RE JUST
DUMB COUNTRY PEOPLE BUT
WHERE I COME FROM BUT
A LOT OF US VOLUNTEERED.
WHO WOULD LIKE TO VOLUNTEER
FOR THE TANK CORPS?
FOR THE AIR FORCE?
WHO WOULD LIKE TO VOLUNTEER
FOR THE NAVY OR WHATEVER?
AND THEN THEY SAID
"WHO WOULD LIKE TO VOLUNTEER
FOR THE AIRBORNE?"
SOMEBODY SAYS "WHAT THE
HELL'S THE AIRBORNE?"
NOBODY EVER HEARD OF IT.
WE CAME FROM
A SMALL SMALL TOWN
AND THREE FELLAS IN THAT TOWN
WERE THAT WERE "4F"
COMMITTED SUICIDE
BECAUSE THEY COULDN'T GO
A DIFFERENT TIME.
I DID THINGS.
I DIDN'T DO 'EM
FOR MEDALS
FOR ACCOLADES.
I DID 'EM BECAUSE
IT'S WHAT HAD TO BE DONE.
THE GUY SAYS "WOULD YOU
JUMP OUT OF AIRPLANES?
"YOU KNOW YOU GOT
ALL YOUR ARMY EQUIPMENT
AND YOU JUMP OUT OF AIRPLANES
TO FIGHT THE ENEMY."
THESE GUYS THEY SAID
"GO TO HELL".
NOBODY PUT UP
THEIR HANDS.
AND THEN I DON'T KNOW
WHAT IT WAS BROUGHT IT UP
BUT THE GUY GIVING
THE SPEECH WAS SAYING
"BUT YOU GET PAID
$50 A MONTH MORE."
SO THAT MADE IT
A HUNDRED BUCKS.
( chattering )
( male )
I WANT A WHIFF
OF CHICKEN PIE.
( male )
OKAY BOYS LET'S
GET THIS GEAR STOWED.
FOX COMPANY
WE GO IN FIVE.
( male )
IN THE NAME OF THE FATHER
AND THE SON AND OF THE HOLY...
( male )
1st PLATOON
DRAW SMALL ARMS.
DO YOU NEED A HAND
LIEUTENANT?
( male )
"EASY COMPANY!"
LISTEN UP!
GATHER UP AROUND ME.
JUST MOVE IT UP
C'MON GENTLEMEN.
LET'S GO!
NOW THE CHANNEL COAST IS
SOCKED IN WITH RAIN AND FOG.
HIGH WINDS ON
THE DROP ZONE.
NO JUMP TONIGHT.
THE INVASION
HAS BEEN POSTPONED.
WE'RE ON A 24
HOUR STAND-DOWN.
SONOFABITCH.
DRILL SERGEANTS
TAKE CHARGE.
Well this is
quite a surprise.
Not particularly.
It so happens
I rather expected it
Well I can't
see how you people
can pass up $80000
for the cause.
For whose cause?
If you're so interested
in serving a cause
why don't you
join the army?
Oh...
I THINK
IT'S CLEARING UP.
YOU THINK
IT'S CLEARING UP?
NO.
I THINK
IT'S CLEARING UP.
HOW ARE YOUR MEN?
THEY'LL BE FINE.
FIVE O'CLOCK
IN NEW YORK.
FOUR O'CLOCK
IN CHICAGO.
HAPPY HOUR HUH?
YEAH.
HAPPY HOUR.
A COUPLE OF DRINKS
MAYBE AN EARLY DINNER
BEFORE THE THEATER.
A CIVILIZED PLACE
FOR CIVILIZED MEN.
SHOULD'VE BEEN
BORN EARLIER NIX.
WHAT AND GIVE
UP ALL THIS?
WE'LL GO TO CHICAGO
I'LL TAKE YOU THERE.
YEAH.
WE'LL SEE.
ACTUALLY YOU KNOW
WHO'S FROM THERE?
WHO?
OH HIM.
712 DAYS OF THAT
SONOFABITCH AND
HERE WE ARE.
( flies buzzing )
YOU PEOPLE ARE AT
THE POSITION OF ATTENTION.
PRIVATE PERCONTE
HAVE YOU BEEN
BLOUSING YOUR TROUSERS
OVER YOUR BOOTS
LIKE A PARATROOPER?
NO SIR.
THEN EXPLAIN
THE CREASES
AT THE BOTTOM.
NO EXCUSE SIR.
VOLUNTEERING FOR THE
PARACHUTE INFANTRY IS
ONE THING PERCONTE
BUT YOU'VE GOT A LONG WAY TO
PROVE THAT YOU BELONG HERE.
YOUR WEEKEND PASS
IS REVOKED.
NAME?
LUZ GEORGE.
DIRT IN THE REAR
SIDE APERTURE.
PASS REVOKED.
WHEN DID YOU SEW
ON THESE CHEVRONS
SERGEANT LIPTON?
YESTERDAY SIR.
LONG ENOUGH
TO NOTICE THIS.
REVOKED.
SIR.
NAME?
MALARKEY DONALD G.
MALARKEY?
MALARKEY'S SLANG
FOR BULLSHIT
ISN'T IT?
YES SIR.
RUST ON THE BUTT
PLATE HINGE SPRING
PRIVATE BULLSHIT.
REVOKED.
NAME?
LIEBGOTT
JOSEPH D SIR.
RUSTY BAYONET
LIEBGOTT.
YOU WANNA
KILL GERMANS?
YES SIR.
NOT WITH THIS.
I WOULDN'T TAKE THIS
RUSTY PIECE OF SHIT TO WAR
AND I WILL NOT TAKE YOU
TO WAR IN YOUR CONDITION.
NOW THANKS TO THESE MEN
AND THEIR INFRACTIONS
EVERY MAN IN THE COMPANY
WHO HAD A WEEKEND PASS
HAS LOST IT.
CHANGE INTO YOUR "PT" GEAR
WE'RE RUNNING CURRAHEE.
2nd PLATOON
FALL OUT.
WE HAVE TWO MINUTES.
FALL OUT!
I AIN'T GOING UP
THAT HILL.
HEY PERCONTE
WHAT ARE YOU
THINKING OF
BLOUSIN' YOUR PANTS?
SHUT UP MARTIN
ALRIGHT?
HE GIGGED EVERYBODY.
YEAH WELL
YOU SHOULD KNOW BETTER.
DON'T GIVE HIM
NO EXCUSES.
EXCUSES?
WHY DON'T YOU COME HERE
LOOK AT THESE TROUSERS
GET DOWN AND YOU
TELL ME IF THERE'S
A CREASE ON 'EM?
ALRIGHT LET'S GO
ON THE ROAD IN
"PT" FORMATION.
LET'S MOVE
MOVE MOVE!
PERCONTE LET'S GO
PERCONTE.
PRIVATE WHITE
WHY ARE YOU NOT
IN YOUR PT GEAR?
I ASKED YOU
A QUESTION PRIVATE.
OH "EASY COMPANY".
AND WHILE YOU'RE RUNNING
DON'T WORRY
WE'LL TAKE YOUR DAMES
TO THE MOVIES FOR YOU.
YEAH GOOD THEY NEED
SOME FEMALE COMPANY.
( male )
WHERE DO WE RUN?
( together )
CURRAHEE.
AND WHAT DOES
"CURRAHEE" MEAN?
WE STAND ALONE.
HOW FAR UP
HOW FAR DOWN?
THREE MILES UP
THREE MILES DOWN.
AND WHAT COMPANY
IS THIS?
"EASY COMPANY."
AND WHAT DO WE DO?
STAND ALONE.
DO NOT HELP
THAT MAN!
THAT MAN.
WE DO NOT STOP.
YOU'VE GOT 30 MINUTES TO GET
TO THE TOP OF THIS MOUNTAIN
IF YOU WANNA SERVE
IN THE PARATROOPERS.
HI-HO SILVER!
C'MON YOU CAN
MAKE IT UP THERE.
C'MON.
C'MON NOW C'MON
ALLEY LET'S GO.
C'MON GUARNERE.
CHRISTENSON
C'MON.
I NEVER THOUGHT I'D SEE
THE DAY PRIVATE WYNN.
WE ARE COMING ON
23 MINUTES.
THAT MAY BE GOOD ENOUGH
FOR THE REST OF THE 506
BUT THAT IS NOT GOOD ENOUGH
FOR "EASY COMPANY".
WE CAN MAKE IT
WE CAN DO THIS C'MON.
I'M GONNA
SAY SOMETHING.
TO WHO?
LIEUTENANT WINTERS.
WHAT IS IT?
PERMISSION TO
SPEAK SIR?
PERMISSION GRANTED.
SIR WE GOT
NINE COMPANIES SIR.
THAT WE DO.
WELL HOW COME WE'RE
THE ONLY COMPANY
MARCHING EVERY FRIDAY NIGHT
1 2 MILES FULL PACK
IN THE PITCH DARK?
WHY DO YOU THINK
PRIVATE RANDLEMAN?
LIEUTENANT SOBEL
HATES US SIR.
DOES NOT HATE
"EASY COMPANY"
PRIVATE RANDLEMAN.
HE JUST HATES YOU.
THANK YOU SIR.
HE HATES HIM BACK.
HE HATES YOU
TOO MUCK.
LIEUTENANT WINTERS I WANT
CANTEENS OUT OF BELTS
WITH THE CAPS
UNSCREWED.
"EASY COMPANY"
CANTEENS OUT AND OPEN.
ON MY COMMAND THEY WILL POUR
THE CONTENTS ONTO THE GROUND.
ON THE CO's ORDER YOU WILL
UPEND YOUR CANTEEN.
NOW LIEUTENANT.
POUR 'EM.
WHO IS THIS?
CHRISTENSON.
WHY IS THERE NO WATER
IN YOUR CANTEEN?
YOU DRANK FROM YOUR
CANTEEN DIDN'T YOU?
SIR I--
LIEUTENANT WINTERS.
YES SIR.
WAS THIS MAN ORDERED
TO NOT DRINK
FROM HIS CANTEEN
DURING THE FRIDAY
NIGHT MARCH?
HE WAS SIR.
PRIVATE CHRISTENSON
YOU HAVE DISOBEYED
A DIRECT ORDER.
YOU WILL FILL
YOUR CANTEEN
AND REPEAT ALL
12 MILES OF THE
MARCH IMMEDIATELY.
YES SIR.
FALL OUT!
WHAT IN THE NAME
OF GOD ARE YOU
DOING WITH MY COMPANY?
YOU'RE LATE AND
YOU ALLOW TROOPERS
TO DISOBEY
DIRECT ORDERS?
NO EXCUSE SIR.
YOU'RE MAKING ME
LOOK BAD LIEUTENANT.
THIS IS NOT
"DOG COMPANY".
"FOX COMPANY".
THIS THIS IS
"EASY COMPANY".
AND UNDER MY COMMAND
THIS WILL BE THE FIRST
AND FINEST COMPANY
IN THIS REGIMENT.
I WANT THE NAMES
OF SIX MEN
THEIR INFRACTIONS
AND YOUR DISCIPLINARY
RECOMMENDATIONS
ON MY DESK
BY 0130.
IS THAT CLEAR?
WHAT INFRACTIONS
SIR?
FIND SOME.
SO WHAT'D YOU DO?
PICKED SIX MEN AND
GAVE 'EM LATRINE DUTY.
THE LUCKY SIX?
MCDONALD TOYE
PERCONTE
LIPTON
MUCK AND GUARNERE.
WHY THEM?
IT WAS THEIR TURN.
SOBEL'S A GENIUS.
I HAD A HEADMASTER JUST
LIKE HIM IN PREP SCHOOL.
I KNOW THE TYPE.
LEWIS
MICHELANGELO'S A GENIUS
BEETHOVEN'S A GENIUS.
YOU KNOW A MAN
IN THIS COMPANY
WHO WOULDN'T
DOUBLE-TIME CURRAHEE
WITH A FULL PACK
JUST TO PISS
IN THAT GUY'S
MORNING COFFEE?
( Sobel )
LET'S GO LET'S GO.
STAND IN THE DOOR.
GO.
ONE THOUSAND
TWO THOUSAND.
YOU JUST BROKE BOTH
YOUR LEGS PRIVATE GORDON.
ARE YOU TRYING TO
GET YOURSELF KILLED?
NO SIR.
STAND IN THE DOOR.
( loud chattering )
SHIT.
TO THE WALL
TO THE WALL.
OVER AS A TEAM.
GO ON
AGAINST THE WALL.
JESUS WHAT
THE HELL IS THIS?
THAT'S PIG GUTS BOY.
GODDAMMIT!
WHY ARE YOU HERE
PRIVATE GORDON?
I WANNA BE IN
THE AIRBORNE SIR.
I DON'T BELIEVE YOU.
WHY ARE YOU HERE
PRIVATE GORDON?
I WANNA BE IN
THE AIRBORNE SIR.
YOU HAVE 50 MINUTES
TO THE TOP AND BACK
AND I WILL BE
WATCHING YOU.
WHAT ARE YOU
WAITING FOR?
"EASY COMPANY" HAS
THE FINEST PERFORMANCE RECORD
IN THE ENTIRE
2nd BATTALION.
I BELIEVE EVERY
BIT OF THAT IS
THANKS TO YOU.
CONGRATULATIONS
CAPTAIN SOBEL.
THANK YOU SIR.
ISN'T THAT
LIEUTENANT WINTERS LEADING
"EASY COMPANY" IN "PT"?
YES SIR.
HE'S A DAMNED
GOOD MAN.
I WAS PLANNING ON
GIVING HIM A SET
OF THESE TODAY.
WHY DON'T
YOU DO IT?
HE'D BE PROUD
TO GET 'EM FROM YOU.
PORNOGRAPHY
CONTRABAND.
NON-REGULATION CLOTHING
THIS MAN HAD
200 PROPHYLACTIC KITS
IN HIS FOOTLOCKER.
HOW IN THE NAME OF GOD WAS
HE GONNA HAVE THE STRENGTH
TO FIGHT THE WAR?
HOW IS IT PRIVATE
PRIVATE TIPPER
HAS SPARE TIME
FOR SO MUCH
CORRESPONDENCE?
CAPTAIN ARE
PERSONAL LETTERS TO BE
CONSIDERED CONTRABAND?
THESE MEN AREN'T
PARATROOPERS YET
LIEUTENANT.
THEY HAVE NO
PERSONAL PROPERTY.
WHAT IS THIS?
ANYBODY?
ER IT'S A CAN
OF PEACHES SIR.
LIEUTENANT NIXON
THINKS THIS IS A
CAN OF PEACHES.
THAT IS INCORRECT
LIEUTENANT.
YOUR WEEKEND PASS
IS CANCELLED.
THIS IS UNITED STATES
ARMY PROPERTY
WHICH WAS TAKEN
WITHOUT AUTHORIZATION
FROM MY MESS FACILITY
AND I WILL NOT TOLERATE
THIEVERY IN MY UNIT.
WHOSE FOOTLOCKER
IS THIS?
PRIVATE PARKES SIR.
GET RID OF HIM.
ALL WEEKEND PASSES
ARE CANCELLED.
OFFICERS INCLUDED.
CARRY ON.
LIEUTENANT WINTERS.
COLONEL SINK HAS SEEN
FIT TO PROMOTE YOU.
AS 1st LIEUTENANT
YOU'LL SERVE AS MY
EXECUTIVE OFFICER.
CONGRATULATIONS.
THANK YOU SIR.
AND AS A TEST OF YOUR
ORGANIZATIONAL SKILLS
AND COMMAND POTENTIAL
I AM DESIGNATING YOU...
MESS OFFICER
FOR 14 DAYS.
REPORT TO THE MESS
KITCHEN AT 0515 HOURS.
COMPANY BREAKFAST
TO BE SERVED AT 0600.
YES SIR.
OH AND DICK...
THERE'S RAIN
FORECAST TOMORROW
SO THE COMPANY WILL
HAVE A LIGHT AFTERNOON
OF LECTURE AND
CLASSROOM INSTRUCTION.
I THINK A SPECIAL MEAL
BEFORE THEIR AFTERNOON OFF
WOULD BE A WELCOME
CHANGE OF PACE.
WOULD YOU AGREE?
YES SIR.
I LIKE SPAGHETTI.
HOLD ON MORE COMING.
THESE GUYS ARE
PACKING IT AWAY.
THIS STUFF
IS ORANGE.
SPAGHETTI AIN'T
SUPPOSED TO
BE ORANGE.
THIS AIN'T SPAGHETTI.
THIS IS ARMY NOODLES
WITH KETCHUP.
YOU AIN'T
GOTTA EAT IT.
OH C'MON GONORRHEA
AS A FELLOW ITALIAN
YOU SHOULD KNOW
THAT CALLING THIS
CRAP SPAGHETTI
IS A MORTAL SIN.
YOU DON'T WANT IT
I'LL HAVE IT.
NO NO NO
I'M EATING HERE.
HEY GET OUTTA HERE.
ORDERS CHANGED
GET UP!
LECTURES
ARE CANCELLED.
"EASY COMPANY"
IS RUNNING UP CURRAHEE.
MOVE MOVE!
THREE MILES UP
THREE MILES DOWN.
HI-HO SILVER!
LET'S GO LET'S GO.
YOU'RE A WASHOUT
PRIVATE HOOBLER!
YOU SHOULD PACK
UP BOTH YOUR EARS
AND GO HOME.
LOOKS LIKE
GORDON'S DONE.
AREN'T YOU GORDON
YOU FINISHED?
YOU DO NOT DESERVE
TO GET YOUR WINGS.
PRIVATE RANDLEMAN
YOU LOOK TIRED.
THERE'S AN AMBULANCE
WAITING FOR YOU AT
THE BOTTOM OF THE HILL.
IT CAN ALL BE
OVER RIGHT NOW.
NO MORE PAIN
NO MORE CURRAHEE.
NO MORE
CAPTAIN SOBEL.
( chanting )
WE PULL UPON THE RISERS
WE FALL UPON THE GRASS
WE NEVER LAND UPON OUR FEET
WE ALWAYS HIT OUR ASS.
AYE AYE CHRIST ALMIGHTY
WHO THE HELL ARE WE
ZIM-ZAM GODDAMN
WE'RE AIRBORNE INFANTRY
WE PULL UPON THE RISERS
WE FALL UPON THE GRASS
WE NEVER LAND UPON OUR FEET
WE ALWAYS HIT OUR ASS
HIDE TIDEE CHRIST ALMIGHTY
WHO THE HELL ARE WE
ZIM-ZAM GODDAMN
WE'RE AIRBORNE INFANTRY.
SO DO WE FEEL LIKE
WE'RE READY TO BE
ARMY PARATROOPERS?
( together )
YES SERGEANT.
I HOPE SO.
THIS'LL BE THE
FIRST OF FIVE EXITS
FROM A C47 AIRCRAFT
SCHEDULED FOR TODAY.
GET READY.
STAND UP.
HOOK UP.
( Sargeant )
UPON SUCCESSFUL COMPLETION
OF YOUR FIFTH AND FINAL JUMP
YOU'LL BE CERTIFIED
ARMY PARATROOPERS.
CHECK EQUIPMENT!
SOUND-OFF FOR
EQUIPMENT CHECK!
NINE OKAY.
EIGHT OKAY.
SEVEN OKAY.
SIX OKAY.
FIVE OKAY.
FOUR OKAY.
THREE OKAY.
TWO OKAY.
ONE OKAY.
THERE'LL BE A LOT OF MEN
DROPPING FROM THE SKY TODAY.
HOPEFULLY UNDER
DEPLOYED CANOPIES.
STAND IN THE DOOR!
I GUARANTEE YOU'RE GONNA
LOVE IT LIEUTENANT.
GO GO!
JUMPING FRO
IN STICKS OF 12 JUMPERS
PER AIRCRAFT.
ALL YOU HAVE TO DO IS
REMEMBER WHAT YOU WERE TAUGHT
AND I GUARANTEE YOU GRAVITY
WILL TAKE CARE OF THE REST.
GO GO GO GO!
GO GO GO!
DAMNIT.
AND GENTLEMEN
REST ASSURED
ANY REFUSALS IN THE AIRCRAFT
OR AT THE DOOR...
AND I GUARANTEE YOU
YOU WILL...
BE OUT OF
THE AIRBORNE.
FOUR OKAY.
THREE OKAY.
TWO OKAY.
ONE OKAY.
STAND IN THE DOOR.
GO!
1000 2000 3000
4000 5000 6000
7000 8000 9000!
( cheering )
HI-HO SILVER.
NOW JUST THINK IF YOU HAD
ANY CLASS OR STYLE LIKE ME
SOMEBODY MIGHT
MISTAKE YOU FOR SOMEBODY.
YOU MEAN LIKE YOUR
FUCKING SERGEANT?
I'M JUST KIDDING.
CONGRATULATIONS
MARTIN.
CORPORAL TOYE THERE WILL BE
NO LEANING IN MY COMPANY.
ARE THOSE DUSTY
JUMP WINGS?
HOW DO YOU EXPECT TO
SLAY THE HUNS
WITH DUST ON
YOUR JUMP WINGS?
LUZ JUST GIVE
ME A DRINK.
HELL OF AN IDEA JOE.
THERE YOU GO.
THREE MILES UP
THREE MILES DOWN.
TEN-HUT!
WELL AT EASE
PARATROOPERS.
GOOD EVENING
"EASY COMPANY".
EVENING SIR.
NOW PARACHUTE INFANTRY
IS A BRAND NEW CONCEPT
IN AMERICAN
MILITARY HISTORY.
BUT BY GOD THE 506 IS GONNA
FORGE THAT BRAND NEW CONCEPT
INTO VICTORY.
YES SIR.
I WANT YOU TO KNOW THAT
I'M DAMNED PROUD
OF EACH AND EVERY
ONE OF YOU.
NOW YOU DESERVE
THIS PARTY.
THANK YOU
SERGEANT GRANT.
SIR.
SO I WANT YOU
TO HAVE FUN...
AND REMEMBER
OUR MOTTO...
CURRAHEE!
( cheering )
PETTY.
MAP.
C'MON.
AH CHRIST.
WE'RE IN THE
WRONG POSITION.
WE'RE TEXTBOOK POSITION
FOR AMBUSH SIR.
WE SHOULD SIT TIGHT
LET THE ENEMY TEAM COME
INTO OUR KILLING ZONE.
THEY'RE RIGHT OUT
THERE SOMEWHERE.
LET'S JUST
GET 'EM.
SIR WE HAVE
PERFECT COVER HERE.
LIEUTENANT
DEPLOY YOUR TROOPS.
2nd PLATOON
MOVE OUT.
WHAT?
TACTICAL COLUMN.
CAPTAIN YOU'VE
JUST BEEN KILLED
ALONG WITH 95 PERCENT
OF YOUR COMPANY.
YOUR OUTFIT?
"EASY COMPANY"
2nd BATTALION 506th.
LEAVE THREE WOUNDED
MEN ON THE GROUND
AND REPORT BACK TO
THE ASSEMBLY AREA.
GODDAMMIT.
YOU YOU YOU.
WELL WHAT ARE
YOU GONNA DO?
NOTHING JUST KEEP
TRAINING THE MEN.
AM I INTERRUPTING?
NO NO.
LIEUTENANT LEWIS NIXON.
LIEUTENANT HARRY WELSH
JUST IN FROM THE 82nd.
CONGRATULATIONS
ON THE PROMOTION.
AH THANKS IF YOU
WANNA CALL IT THAT.
YOU'LL LEARN HIM
PRETTY QUICKLY
NO FLAWS NO VICES
NO SENSE OF HUMOR.
JUST LIKE YOUR CHUMS
UP AT BATTALION STAFF.
WHAT'S UP?
I'M HEARING A LOT
OF RUMBLINGS.
SOBEL?
JUST TALKING
ABOUT THAT.
SO HE GETS A LITTLE
JUMPY IN THE FIELD?
HMM-MMM.
HE GETS JUMPY AND
THEN YOU GET KILLED.
THAT'S NICE.
YEAH LISTEN
IF WE DISCUSS IT
I THINK IT SHOULD JUST
BE AMONGST OURSELVES.
OH ABSOLUTELY.
2nd PLATOON READY?
READY SIR.
THEN GET THEM
IN FORMATION.
WE'RE MOVING OUT.
YES SIR.
( laughing )
SHUT UP COBB.
EH YOU GOTTA
ADMIT IT.
HE'S GOT
NO CHANCE.
EITHER THE KRAUTS
WILL GET HIM
OR ONE OF US.
WHO SOBEL?
HE SCREWED UP
ONE MANEUVER.
WELL YOU KNOW
I'M ALWAYS FUMBLING
WITH GRENADES.
IT WOULD BE EASY
IF ONE WENT OFF BY
ACCIDENT YOU KNOW?
WELL NOW THEY
MUST HAVE PUT HIM IN
CHARGE FOR A REASON.
YEAH 'CAUSE THE
ARMY WOULDN'T MAKE A
MISTAKE RIGHT SHIFT?
GOING MY WAY?
WHEREVER THE TRAIN
TAKES ME.
WHERE DO YOU SUPPOSE
THAT MIGHT BE?
I HAVEN'T
GOT A CLUE.
YEAH C'MON
TAKE A GUESS.
ATLANTIC PACIFIC
ATLANTIC?
I'M NOT THE
INTELLIGENCE OFFICER.
MMM.
WELL AS SUCH
I OF COURSE KNOW
BUT IF I TOLD YOU
I'D HAVE TO KILL YOU.
SO DON'T TELL ME.
NEW YORK CITY.
TROOP SHIP.
ENGLAND.
WE'RE INVADING EUROPE
MY FRIEND.
FORTRESS EUROPA.
SINCE WHEN
DO I DRINK?
IF I THOUGHT YOU'D
DRINK IT I WOULDN'T
OFFER IT TO YOU.
NIX?
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO
WHEN YOU GET INTO COMBAT?
OH I HAVE EVERY CONFIDENCE
IN MY SCROUNGING ABILITIES.
AND I HAVE A CASE OF VAT 69
HIDDEN IN YOUR FOOTLOCKER.
REALLY?
OH YEAH.
MORNING.
MMM.
THIS COULD
TURN INTO A
REAL NICE TRIP.
( Sobel )
"DEAR SIR OR MADAM
"SOON YOUR SON WILL
DROP FROM THE SKY
"TO ENGAGE AND
DEFEAT THE ENEMY.
"YOUR FREQUENT LETTERS OF
LOVE AND ENCOURAGEMENT
"WILL ARM HIM
WITH A FIGHTING HEART.
"WITH THAT HE CANNOT FAIL
BUT WILL WIN GLORY FOR HIMSELF
"MAKE YOU PROUD OF HIM
AND HIS COUNTRY EVER GRATEFUL
"FOR HIS SERVICE
IN ITS HOUR OF NEED.
SIGNED HERBERT M. SOBEL
CAPTAIN COMMANDING."
RIGHT NOW SOME LUCKY BASTARD'S
HEADED FOR THE SOUTH PACIFIC.
OH WHAT I'D GIVE.
HE'S GONNA GET BILLETED
ON SOME TROPICAL ISLAND...
KEEP TALKING.
SITTING UNDER A PALM TREE
WITH SIX NAKED NATIVE GIRLS
HELPING HIM
CUT UP COCONUTS
SO HE CAN HAND-FEED 'EM
TO THE FLAMINGOS.
FLAMINGOS ARE MEAN.
THEY BITE.
SO DO THE NAKED
NATIVE GIRLS.
WITH ANY LUCK.
HEY GUYS I'M GLAD
I'M GOING TO EUROPE.
HITLER GETS ONE OF THESE
RIGHT ACROSS THE WINDPIPE.
ROOSEVELT CHANGES THANKSGIVING
TO JOE TOYE DAY
AND PAYS ME 10 GRAND
A YEAR FOR THE REST
OF MY FUCKING LIFE.
WHAT IF WE DON'T
GET TO EUROPE?
WHAT IF THEY SEND US
TO NORTH AFRICA?
MY BROTHER'S
IN NORTH AFRICA.
HE SAYS IT'S HOT.
REALLY IT'S HOT
IN AFRICA?
SHUT UP.
THE POINT IS IT DON'T
MATTER WHERE WE GO.
ONCE WE GET INTO COMBAT
THE ONLY PERSON YOU CAN TRUST
IS YOURSELF AND THE
FELLA NEXT TO YOU.
HEY AS LONG AS
HE'S A PARATROOPER.
OH YEAH?
AND WHAT IF THAT PARATROOPER
TURNS OUT TO BE SOBEL?
IF I'M NEXT TO SOBEL
IN COMBAT I'M MOVING
ON DOWN THE LINE.
HOOK UP WITH
SOME OTHER OFFICER
LIKE HEYLIGER
OR WINTERS.
I LIKE WINTERS
HE'S A GOOD MAN.
BUT WHEN THE BULLETS
START FLYING
I DON'T KNOW IF I
WANT A QUAKER DOING
MY FIGHTING FOR ME.
HOW DO YOU KNOW
HE'S A QUAKER?
HE AIN'T CATHOLIC.
NEITHER'S SOBEL.
THAT PRICK'S
THE SON OF ABRAHAM.
HE'S WHAT?
HE'S A JEW.
I'M A JEW.
CONGRATULATIONS.
GET YOUR NOSE
OUT OF MY FACE.
WHAT'S ALL
THAT ABOUT?
GONORRHEA CALLED
SOBEL A JEW.
LIEBGOTT TOOK OFFENSE
'CAUSE HE'S A JEW TOO.
FIGHTING OVER SOBEL
THAT'S SMART.
ATTACK!
NO YOU WANNA
KILL HIM!
PARRY RIGHT
PARRY LEFT.
THRUST!
TAKE COVER.
OKAY.
YESTERDAY WE TALKED ABOUT
MAGNETIC DECLINATION
AND THE LEFT ADD
RIGHT SUBTRACT RULE.
TODAY WE'RE GONNA
PUT IT INTO PRACTICE.
THERE ARE TWO BASIC TYPES
OF FIGHTING POSITIONS.
THE FIRST IS
THE PREPARED POSITION.
THE ADVANTAGES
OF A PREPARED POSITION
ARE THAT IT GIVES YOU
COVER AND CONCEALMENT.
COMMENCE FIRE!
WE'LL THEN MANEUVER
RIGHT IN THROUGH
THESE TREES.
AT THE SAME TIME
OUR 2nd PLATOON
IN THIS PARTICULAR CASE
MOVES OVER HERE.
HE'S THEN GONNA CLOSE
WITH AND KILL OR
CAPTURE THAT GERMAN.
( panting )
SOBEL'S LATE.
WHY IS THERE
A FENCE HERE?
THERE SHOULD BE
NO FENCE HERE.
TIPPER!
YES SIR.
GIVE ME THE MAP.
PERCONTE LUZ.
GET THE MEN
GET 'EM B--
TAKE COVER BEHIND
THOSE TREES.
ALRIGHT YOU
HEARD THE WORD.
THERE SHOULD BE
NO THERE SHOULD
BE NO FENCE HERE.
UM...
( clearing throat )
WE COULD GO
OVER IT SIR.
REALLY?
THAT'S NOT THE POINT
WHERE ARE THE GODDAMN--
WHERE THE GODDAMN
HELL ARE WE?
PERCONTE?
YEAH.
SOBEL'S LOST AGAIN
RIGHT?
YEAH HE'S LOST.
FUCKING CHRIST.
CAN YOU DO
MAJOR HORTON?
( as John Wayne )
DOES A WILD BEAR CRAP
IN THE WOODS SON?
SHH SHH SHH.
MAYBE THE GOOD
MAJOR CAN GOOSE
THIS SCHMUCK.
GET US MOVING?
NO WAY...
OH YEAH YES.
YOU GOTTA
YOU GOTTA.
ALRIGHT
JUST THIS ONCE.
SHH SHH.
THREE FIVE
SIX EIGHT
THREE THREE.
ISN'T THAT
THE INTERSECTION?
NO SIR IT'S HERE.
YOU'RE A FULL
GRID OFF.
GODDAMMIT.
IS THERE A PROBLEM
CAPTAIN SOBEL?
WHO SAID THAT?
WHO BROKE SILENCE?
I THINK IT'S
MAJOR HORTON SIR.
MAJOR HORTON?
WHAT IS HE
DID HE JOIN US?
I THINK MAYBE HE'S MOVING
BETWEEN THE PLATOONS SIR.
WHAT IS THE GODDAMN
HOLDUP MR. SOBEL?
A FENCE SIR.
UM GOD...
A BARBED WIRE FENCE.
OH THAT DOG
JUST AIN'T GONNA HUNT.
NOW YOU CUT THAT FENCE
AND GET THIS GODDAMN PLATOON
ON THE MOVE!
YES SIR!
WHERE ARE MY GODDAMN
WIRE CUTTERS?
WE HAVE TO MOVE.
SIR WITHOUT CAPTAIN
SOBEL AND 1 st PLATOON?
IT'S A "T" INTERSECTION.
WE IMPROVISE.
DOUBLE ENVELOPMENT
LAID ON A BASE OF FIRE
TO CUT THE ROAD
IN ALL DIRECTIONS.
HOOK RIGHT
WITH 1 st SQUAD.
TELL GUARNERE TO
MOVE LEFT WITH 2nd.
I'LL BE RIGHT UP
THE MIDDLE WITH 3rd GO.
YES SIR.
DEARY ME.
( dog barking )
BLOODY HELL.
YOU'VE DONE
IT NOW YANKS.
YOU'VE CAPTURED ME.
HI-HO SILVER!
WOULD THAT BE
THE ENEMY?
AS A MATTER
OF FACT YES.
GOOD WORK
2nd PLATOON.
WE TOOK
THE OBJECTIVE.
WHO IS THE IDIOT WHO
CUT THAT MAN'S FENCE?
I WAS ORDERED TO SIR.
BY WHOM?
MAJOR HORTON SIR.
MAJOR HORTON?
YES SIR.
MAJOR HORTON
TOLD YOU TO DO THAT?
YES SIR.
MAJOR HORTON ORDERED
YOU TO CUT THE FENCE?
YES HE DID.
MAJOR HORTON IS ON
LEAVE IN LONDON.
GET THOSE COWS
OUT OF HERE.
LIEUTENANT WINTERS.
WITH CAPTAIN SOBEL'S
COMPLIMENTS SIR.
LIEUTENANT.
OH FOR CRYING
OUT LOUD.
THIS SPELLS
COURT-MARTIAL.
NO SIR
I DO NOT UNDERSTAND.
YOUR ORDERS TO
ME WERE TO INSPECT
THE LATRINES
AT 1000 HOURS.
FROM 0930 TO 0955
I WAS CENSORING
THE ENLISTED MEN'S MAIL
BY ORDER OF
COLONEL STRAYER.
AT 1 000 HOURS I FOLLOWED
YOUR ORDERS TO THE MINUTE.
I CHANGED THAT
TIME TO 0945.
NO ONE
TOLD ME SIR.
I TELEPHONED.
I'M QUARTERED WITH A FAMILY
THAT HAS NO TELEPHONE.
AND SENT A RUNNER.
NO RUNNER FOUND
ME CAPTAIN.
IRREGARDLESS WHEN GIVEN
A TASK TO PERFORM
BY A RANKING OFFICER
TO ANOTHER OFFICER.
YOU FAILED TO DO SO.
WERE I TO LET
SUCH A FAILURE OF DUTY
BY MY OWN XO GO UNPUNISHED
WHAT KIND OF MESSAGE
IS THAT TO THE MEN?
I PERFORMED MY DUTY
AS I WAS ORDERED SIR.
AND I DISAGREE.
SO YOUR OPTIONS ARE
QUITE SIMPLE LIEUTENANT.
PUNISHMENT FOR YOUR OFFENSES
WILL BE DENIAL OF
A 48-HOUR PASS
FOR 60 DAYS.
STAND BEFORE ME
AT ATTENTION.
OR YOU MAY INITIATE
A LETTER OF APPEAL
AND REQUEST A TRIAL
BY COURT-MARTIAL.
YOU SPEND YOUR WEEKENDS
ON THE BASE ANYWAY DICK.
BE A MAN
TAKE THE PUNISHMENT.
MAY I BORROW
YOUR PEN SIR?
MY ENDORSEMENT SIR.
I REQUEST TRIAL
BY COURT-MARTIAL.
WE LOST WINTERS
TO BATTALION MESS.
YOU'RE SHITTING ME.
NO.
STRAYER DID IT WHILE THEY TRY
TO FIGURE OUT THE PROCEDURES
FOR HIS COURT-MARTIAL.
WELL NIX BETTER
FIND A LOOPHOLE
AND GET HIM OUT.
AND IF HE DON'T?
WINTERS SCRAMBLES EGGS
WHILE THE REST OF US MAKE
THE BIG JUMP WITH SOBEL.
NOT ME.
SO WE'RE GOING THROUGH
WITH THIS RIGHT?
WE'VE GOTTA
DO SOMETHING.
YEAH.
ALRIGHT.
GOOD.
BUT WE'D ALL BETTER
BE CLEAR OF THE
CONSEQUENCES.
I DON'T CARE ABOUT
THE CONSEQUENCES.
WE COULD BE LINED UP
AGAINST A WALL AND SHOT.
NOW I'M READY
TO FACE THAT.
AND EVERY ONE OF US
HAD BETTER BE TOO.
I WILL NOT FOLLOW
THAT MAN INTO COMBAT.
ME NEITHER.
ALRIGHT.
THEN LET'S DO IT.
I HEREBY...
NO LONGER...
WISH TO SERVE...
AS A NON-COMMISSIONED
OFFICER...
IN "EASY COMPANY".
ALRIGHT BOYS.
GOOD LUCK.
I OUGHT TO HAVE
YOU ALL SHOT!
THIS IS NOTHING LESS
THAN AN ACT OF MUTINY
WHILE WE PREPARE FOR THE
GODDAMN INVASION OF EUROPE.
SERGEANT HARRIS.
YES SIR.
TURN IN YOUR STRIPES
COLLECT YOUR GEAR.
YOU ARE HEREBY TRANSFERRED
OUT OF MY REGIMENT.
YES SIR.
GET OUT.
SERGEANT RANNEY.
SIR.
YOU CONSIDER YOURSELF
LUCKY I'M ONLY
BUSTING YOU TO PRIVATE.
ALL OF YOU NCOs
HAVE DISGRACED
THE 101st AIRBORNE.
YOU CAN CONSIDER
YOURSELF LUCKY THAT
WE ARE ON THE EVE
OF THE LARGEST
ACTION IN THE
HISTORY OF WARFARE
WHICH LEAVES ME
NO CHOICE BUT TO
SPARE YOUR LIVES.
NOW GET OUT OF MY OFFICE
AND GET OUT OF MY SIGHT.
GET.
KEEP 'EM COMING
THAT-A-BOY.
THAT'S IT.
I CAN ONLY
SPECULATE SIR.
MOST OF THE MEN WOULD
WOULD NEVER DO THIS
BUT I BELIEVE JUST
A FEW OF THE SERGEANTS
MAY HAVE FELT
THEIR LOYALTY LAY
MORE TO THE PLATOON
THAN TO THE COMPANY.
AND THESE FEW SERGEANTS
CONVINCED ALL OF THE OTHER
NCOs IN YOUR COMPANY
TO TURN IN
THEIR STRIPES?
AS STAFF SERGEANTS
THEY HAVE A GREAT AMOUNT
OF INFLUENCE SIR.
BUT AS I SAY
THE REST ARE GOOD MEN.
I KNOW THEM
I CAN WORK WITH THEM.
THIS BUSINESS WITH
THE WINTERS' COURT-MARTIAL
HAS BEEN AN
UNPLEASANT DISTRACTION.
INDEED INDEED
IT HAS SIR.
HOWEVER...
YOUR COMMAND
OF "EASY COMPANY"
HAS BEEN EXEMPLARY.
THANK THANK
YOU SIR.
IN FACT EXCEPT FOR
THE ACTIONS OF A
FEW OF YOUR NONCOMS
I BELIEVE YOU'VE FIELDED
ONE OF THE FINEST
COMPANIES OF SOLDIERS
I'VE EVER SEEN.
YES SIR.
HERBERT DIVISION
HAS ESTABLISHED
A PARACHUTE TRAINING
SCHOOL AT CHILTON FOLIAT.
THE IDEA IS FOR
NON-INFANTRY TYPES WHO...
WERE VITAL TO
THE COMING INVASION
SUCH AS DOCTORS AND CHAPLAINS
TO TAKE JUMP TRAINING THERE.
FRANKLY I CAN'T THINK
OF ANYONE MORE
QUALIFIED TO COMMAND
SUCH A SCHOOL
THAN YOU ARE.
SIR?
I'M REASSIGNING YOU
TO CHILTON FOLIAT.
I'M LOSING
"EASY COMPANY"?
THE WAR EFFORT
NEEDS YOU ELSEWHERE.
PERMISSION TO
SPEAK SIR?
GRANTED.
IS WHO WHO WILL
BE REPLACING ME?
LIEUTENANT MEEHAN FROM
BAKER COMPANY IS SENIOR.
GOOD LUCK AT
CHILTON FOLIAT HERBERT.
DON'T LET US
DOWN NOW.
NO SIR.
CARRY ON.
( male )
2nd PLATOON
LISTEN UP.
I WANT THE 1 st
SQUAD AND A-SIDE
TENTS RIGHT UP THERE.
3rd SQUAD
SECOND ROW...
HOLY SHIT.
NO IT'S ALL RIGHT
MATE WE'RE TOMMIES.
NOT BLEEDIN' BOSCH.
IS ALL THIS REAL?
YEAH YEAH.
WELL SOME OF IT'S
FROM THE HERMANS
THAT SOMEBODY'S
TAILORS KNOCKED UP
FOR YOU LADS ACTUALLY SO
YOU CAN GET YOUR MINCE PIES
ON SOME OF THIS
JERRY CLOBBER IF YOU
KNOW WHAT I MEAN.
NOT REALLY.
EH?
HEY MAC
YOU GOT A LUGER?
I'M DYING TO GET MY
HANDS ON A REAL LUGER.
YEAH GO ON THEN.
QUICK BUTCHERS YEAH?
BOY SHE SURE
IS A DOOZY.
YEAH IT'S
PUKKA INNIT.
WHAT?
HEY PETTY.
HEY MATE.
YOU'RE HAVING A BATH
IF YOU THINK YOU'RE
HALF-INCHING THAT.
OH YEAH.
SORRY.
WELL GOOD LUCK.
YOU TOO MATE.
WHAT'S UP HOOBS?
THESE MEN HAVE BEEN THROUGH
THE TOUGHEST TRAINING
THE ARMY
HAS TO OFFER.
UNDER THE WORST
POSSIBLE CIRCUMSTANCES.
AND THEY VOLUNTEERED
FOR IT.
CHRIST DICK I WAS JUST
SHOOTING CRAPS WITH THEM.
IT'S NOT LIKE...
YOU KNOW WHY
THEY VOLUNTEERED?
SO WHEN THINGS GOT
REALLY BAD THE MAN
IN THE FOXHOLE
NEXT TO THEM
WOULD BE THE BEST.
NOT SOME DRAFTEE WHO'S
GONNA GET HIM KILLED.
ARE YOU TICKED
BECAUSE THEY LIKE ME?
BECAUSE I'M SPENDING TIME
TO GET TO KNOW MY SOLDIERS?
I MEAN C'MON YOU'VE BEEN
WITH THESE GUYS FOR WHAT
TWO YEARS?
I'VE BEEN HERE
FOR SIX DAYS.
YOU'RE GAMBLING BOB.
SO WHAT
SOLDIERS DO THAT.
I DON'T DESERVE
A REPRIMAND FOR IT.
WHAT IF YOU'D WON?
WHAT?
( slowly )
WHAT-IF-YOU'D-WON?
NEVER PUT YOURSELF
IN A POSITION
WHERE YOU CAN TAKE
FROM THESE MEN.
LIEUTENANT MEEHAN?
ENTER.
ON THE LAST TRAINING
JUMP I HAD A COMPASS.
CLOSE THE FLAP.
THEN WE TURN LEFT.
YEAH.
BEARING ZERO FOUR TWO
1 2 MINUTES.
THEN ANOTHER LEFT?
YES.
YEAH.
CALL IT THREE
FIVE EIGHT
FOR 1 0 AND
A HALF MINUTES.
GREEN LIGHT
RIGHT OVER RAMSBURY.
RAMSBURY.
EVERY SINGLE TIME.
LINEAR DISTANCE ON
THE GRID OF ABOUT...
OKAY.
RAMSBURY
UPOTTERY.
SO...
IT'S NORMANDY.
( Nixon )
ST. MARIE DU MONT.
CAUSEWAY NUMBER ONE.
CAUSEWAY NUMBER TWO.
THE ULTIMATE
FIELD PROBLEM.
THE ESTUARY OF
THE DOUVE RIVER
DIVIDES TWO BEACHHEADS
CODE-NAMED UTAH HERE
AND OMAHA HERE.
SEABORNE INFANTRY WILL
HIT THESE BEACHES IN FORCE
AT A DATE AND TIME
TO BE SPECIFIED.
H-HOUR D-DAY.
AIRBORNE'S OBJECTIVE
GENTLEMEN
IS TO TAKE THE TOWN OF
CARELTAN OR CARENTAN
THUS LINKING UTAH AND
OMAHA INTO A SINGLE
CONTINUOUS BEACHHEAD.
... LINKING OMAH AND UTAH
INTO ONE CONTINUOUS BEACHHEAD.
EACH TROOPER WILL
LEARN THIS OPERATION BY HEART
AND KNOW HIS AND EVERY
OTHER OUTFITS' MISSION
TO THE DETAIL.
LIEUTENANT MEEHAN?
YES DUKEMAN.
SIR ARE WE
DROPPING TONIGHT?
WHEN IT'S TIME FOR YOU TO
KNOW WE'LL LET YOU KNOW.
IN THE MEANTIME
STUDY THESE SAND
TABLES MAPS
AND RECONNAISSANCE PHOTOS
UNTIL YOU CAN DRAW A MAP
OF THE AREA BY MEMORY.
NOW WE WILL DROP
BEHIND THIS ATLANTIC WALL
FIVE HOURS BEFORE
THE 4th INFANTRY
LANDS AT UTAH.
AND BETWEEN OUR
ASSEMBLY AREA AND THE
BATTALION'S OBJECTIVE
THERE IS
A GERMAN GARRISON
RIGHT HERE IN THIS AREA
ST. MARIE DU MONT.
"EASY COMPANY" WILL
DESTROY THAT GARRISON.
THREE DAY SUPPLY OF K-RATIONS
CHOCOLATE BARS CHARMS CANDY
POWDERED COFFEE
SUGAR AND MATCHES.
COMPASS BAYONET
ENTRENCHING TOOL
AMMUNITION GAS MASK.
MUSETTE BAG WITH AMMO
MY WEBBING MY.45 CANTEEN
TWO CARTONS OF SMOKES.
HAWKINS MINE
TWO GRENADES
SMOKE GRENADE
GAMMA GRENADE
TNT
THIS BULLSHIT
AND A PAIR OF
NASTY SKIVVIES.
WHAT'S YOUR POINT?
YOU KNOW THIS STUFF
WEIGHS AS MUCH AS I DO.
I'VE STILL GOT MY CHUTE
MY RESERVE CHUTE
MY MAE WEST MY M-1.
WHERE ARE YOU KEEPING
YOUR BRASS KNUCKLES?
I COULD USE SOME
BRASS KNUCKLES.
SERGEANT MARTIN.
HEY VEST
ANYTHING FOR ME?
NO.
SERGEANT MARTIN.
FOR TALBERT.
YOUR CONDOMS?
I DON'T KNOW
PROBABLY.
WHAT YOU GOT?
"DEAR FLOYD
GIVE 'EM HELL."
IT'S FROM CHIEF
OF THE KOKOMO
POLICE DEPARTMENT.
RIGHT.
WHOA YOU'VE
GOTTA LOVE COPS.
ALRIGHT LISTEN
UP LISTEN UP.
IF YOU DID NOT SIGN YOUR
GI LIFE INSURANCE POLICY
YOU GO ON OVER
AND SEE SERGEANT EVANS
AT THE HEADQUARTERS
COMPANY TENT.
YOU BOYS DON'T
LET YOUR FAMILIES
MISS OUT ON
$10000.
YOU HEAR THAT
GERRY?
HEY LIP?
YEAH BOY.
HAS GUARNERE SAID
ANYTHING TO YOU
ABOUT HIS BROTHER?
NO.
I GOT A PROBLEM.
MY WIFE KEEPS UP
WITH THINGS BACK HOME
CASUALTY LISTS
AND LIKE THAT.
YEAH?
GUARNERE'S BROTHER
IN ITALY?
HENRY?
KILLED IN
MONTE CASSINO.
WELL I'M SURE
HE DOESN'T KNOW.
DAMN.
WHAT'D YOU THINK
I SHOULD DO?
IF IT WERE ME
I'D TELL HIM.
COUPLE OF HOURS
BEFORE WE JUMP?
I DON'T KNOW.
WHY THEY SPRINGING
THESE THINGS ON US NOW?
IT'S JUST AN EXTRA 80 POUNDS
STRAPPED TO YOUR LEG.
DOES ANYBODY HAVE ANY IDEA HOW
THE HELL THIS THING WORKS?
COLONEL SINK.
"SOLDIERS OF
THE REGIMENT:
"TONIGHT IS THE NIGHT
"OF NIGHTS.
"TODAY AS YOU READ THIS
YOU ARE EN ROUTE
"TO THE GREAT
ADVENTURE FOR WHICH
YOU HAVE TRAINED FOR
OVER TWO YEARS."
SO THAT'S WHY THEY
GAVE US ICE CREAM.
"EASY COMPANY"
LISTEN UP!
CHANNEL COAST IS SOCKED
IN WITH RAIN AND FOG.
NO JUMP TONIGHT.
THE INVASION
HAS BEEN POSTPONED.
WE'RE ON A 24-HOUR
STAND-DOWN.
Well this is
quite a surprise.
Not particularly.
It so happens
I rather expected it.
Well I can't see
how you people can
pass up $80000
for the cause.
For whose cause?
If you're so interested
in serving a cause
why don't you
join the army?
Next please.
Oh 4-M.
You look
1 -A to me.
Hey you don't
look so bad yourself.
"DEAREST JOHNNY."
Well should you
be giving blood?
I woke up.
I GOT THE WRONG
GODDAMN JACKET.
SHH.
I was struck
by lightning.
Nobody dancing.
It doesn't
matter.
"YOUR PAL BILL
GUARNERE'S BROTHER..."
( panting )
GOOD LUCK LADS.
SEE YOU TOMMY.
SEE YOU MATE.
TRY AND GET THESE
LEG STRAPS THROUGH.
JOHNNY?
GOT SOMETHING
YOU MIGHT BE
LOOKING FOR.
TOOK YOUR JACKET
BY MISTAKE.
I'M SORRY.
YOU READ IT?
WHERE THE FUCK IS
MONTE CASSINO?
I DON'T KNOW.
ITALY SOMEWHERE.
SORRY ABOUT
YOUR BROTHER BILL
HE WAS ER...
LET'S GET
THIS OVER WITH.
BILL?
I'LL MEET UP
WITH YOU OVER THERE.
GENTLEMEN DOC ROE
IS HANDING THESE
OUT FOR AIR SICKNESS.
ORDERS ARE EVERY MAN
TAKES ONE NOW
ANOTHER 30 MINUTES
IN THE AIR.
LIEUTENANT.
2nd PLATOON
LISTEN UP.
GOOD LUCK.
GOD BLESS YOU.
I'LL SEE YOU IN
THE ASSEMBLY AREA.
IF THE WIRE CONSTANT
IS SENSITIVE
THEN I THINK ALL
WE SHOULD HAVE TO
DEAL WITH IS...
GODDAMN LIEB.
THAT AIRSICK PILL
IS MAKING ME LOOPY.
Captions Copyright 2001
HOME BOX OFFICE
A Division of TIME WARNER
ENTERTAINMENT COMPANY L.P.
Captioned by
HBO COMMUNICATIONS CENTE